

NAJI ALHUSAMI

Front-End Developer

My Contact

Nationality: Syrian.

Stanbul, Turkey

majihussami@gmail.com

in <u>Naji</u>

<u>NajiAlhusami</u>

Date of Birth: 01/01/1994

+90 535 681 22 79

Portfolio

<u>NajiAlhusami</u>

About Me

Web Developer passionate about Front-End Web development. Well-versed in JavaScript and React to build/improve Frontend Web applications, with a strong skill set in Multi-tasking and a background in the networking field. Joining UNDP to deploy their project was one of my best experiences.

Education

Frontend Web Development - Re:Coded

Sep 2022 - Jan 2023

Re: Coded Immersive Bootcamps are highly competitive, with a 5% acceptance rate.

- Completing a 4.5-month immersive design Bootcamp, with 300+ hours of curricula, more than 100 assignments, and project-based learning.
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Redux.
- Working with various design teams to create products across industries.

LINK: Certificate URL

Master of Science in Computer Engineering - Bahçeşehir University

Feb 2020 - Jul 2022

- Specializations in Data Mining, Network Security, and Computer Vision.
- Strong course in AGILE Methodologies.

Bachelor of Science in Information Systems Engineering - Eastern Mediterranean University

Oct 2011— Jun 2016

• Specializations in Networking, Telecommunication and Programming.

Experience

Frontend Web Developer - UNDP (SDG AI LAB)

Oct 2021 - Jan 2022 / Remote Volunteer

- Improved the existing software (Digital Technologies Radar development) as measured by SDG AI Lab, by using React and TypeScript.
- Accomplished deployment of the existing software measured by SDG Al Lab, using Gatsby.
- Gained great experience from the UNDP community.

LINKS: UNDP-Volunteers-Link - Certificate URL

IT Help Desk - Syrian Arab Red Crescent (SARC)

Sep 2017 - Oct 2019 /Full Time

Provided help desk services to meet user problems and requests.

IT Networking Engineer - Eastern Mediterranean University

Oct 2016 - May 2017 /Intern

- Installed and configured Routers, Switches and Access Points.
- Troubleshooted hardware and software issues..

Projects

Online Therapist - <u>DEMO | CODE</u>

Dec 2022 - Feb 2023 / Full Time

This was group project, it allows users to take an appointment with a therapist and take therapy sessions online.

- Technologies: Reactjs, Redux and Tailwind CSS.
- Our project was one of the best graduation projects.
- My role was the Redux toolkit part in the project.
- led my team for two weeks out of 6.

Online Food Order App - <u>DEMO</u> | <u>CODE</u>

Feb 2023 / Full Time

It is Application to order food online through the website.

- Technologies: Reactis and CSS.
- It was an individual project.

The Movie Database - DEMO | CODE

Nov 2022 / Full Time

This project allows us to search for the newest Movies and actors from Movie Database (TMDB) which is a community-built movie and TV DB.

- Technologies: JavaScript and Bootstrap.
- Practiced DOM manipulation and 3rd party APIs.
- I was the team lead, I gave tasks for each member.

Hangman Game - DEMO | CODE

Oct 2022 / Full Time

• Technologies: JavaScript.

Mad Libs Game - DEMO | CODE

Oct 2022 / Full Time

• Technologies: JavaScript and CSS.

Courses

JavaScript (The Complete Guide 2023) / 52.5 Hours - UDEMY

• LINK: Credential URL

React (incl Hooks, React Router, Redux) / 48.5 Hours - UDEMY

• LINK: Credential URL

Understanding TypeScript / 15 Hours - UDEMY

• LINK: Credential URL

Technical Skills

HTML CSS Bootstrap Tailwind CSS JavaScript Reactjs Redux TypeScript

Languages

Arabic Native

English Full Professional working proficiency

• Turkish B1 Level.

Soft Skill

- Observation
- Decision making
- Communication
- Multi-tasking
- TeamWork